(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-12T21:16:44.216962",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ケーケー!
Kikkerikii!
ホロライブEnglishのたかなしきあらです!
I'm Takanashi Kiara from Hololive English!
イェーイ! スバル先輩!
Yay! Subaru-senpai!
なんと、なんと、なんと! 5周年なんだと聞いてお祝いしに来ました!
I heard it's your 5th anniversary, so I came to celebrate!
おめでとうございます!
Congratulations!
5年間はマジで特にこの世界ではめちゃくちゃ長いじゃないですか。
Five years is seriously super long, especially in this world, right?
なのに毎日毎日もうデビューしたてな感じで頑張っている姿は本当に本当に尊敬しています。
Yet seeing you work hard every single day just like when you debuted—I honestly, truly respect that.
スバル先輩のように毎日元気でいられたらいいな、私も頑張ります。
I hope I can stay as energetic every day like Subaru-senpai, I'll do my best too!
スバル先輩、これからも...
Subaru-senpai, from now on...
ホロライブの先輩、そしてホロライブの仲間として一緒に頑張ろうね、仲良くしてください。
Let's work hard together as Hololive seniors, and as Hololive friends. Please get along with me!
そして何よりも、今のライブを全力で頑張ってね! 見てるよ! ファイト!
And above all, give it your all in your live stream right now! I'm watching! Fight!
えい、えい、おー!
Ei, ei, oh!
ホロライブの... おるら、おるら、しゅばあちゃん!
Hololive's... Oru... Oru... Shuba-chan!
5周年おめでとう!
Happy 5th anniversary!
どうやらライブもあるみたいじゃん! 頑張ってね!
Sounds like you've got a live concert too! Do your best!
また一緒にゲームで遊ぼう! バイバーイ!
Let's play games together again! Bye-bye!
スバル先輩、5周年おめでとうございます! でござる!
Subaru-senpai, congratulations on your 5th anniversary, de gozaru!
ご、ご、ござるの「ご」でござるな、おめでとうございます!
It's "go" for gozaru, congratulations!
最近はね、裏で一緒にFF14で遊ばせていただいたりとか、ストロクやってるところ見せてもらいつつお話ししたりとかしてて、勝手にすごく距離が縮まったんじゃないかななんて思っています!
Lately, we've been playing FF14 together behind the scenes, and you've let me watch you play Street Fighter while we chat, so I feel like we've gotten a lot closer on my own accord!
いつも構っていただきありがとうございます!
Thank you for always paying attention to me!
スバル先輩のね、元気の姿とかダンスしてる姿は風間にとってお手本なので、これからも一緒にいろんなことをしていけたら嬉しいなと思っております!
Subaru-senpai's energetic self and dancing are such role models for me, so I'd be so happy if we could keep doing various things together from now on!
今日のライブも楽しみにしています! ござるさんと一緒に応援してるでござる! いけるいける、スバル先輩ならいけるでござる!
I'm looking forward to today's live stream too! I'm cheering you on along with Gozaru! You got this, Subaru-senpai can totally do it!
スバル先輩、スバル先輩。
Subaru-senpai, Subaru-senpai.
お疲れ様です!
Good work!
火威青です。
It's Hiyodoshi Ao.
スバル先輩って、もしして...
Subaru-senpai, could it be...
5周年! 5周年なんですよね!? おめでとうございます!
5th anniversary! It's your 5th anniversary, right!? Congratulations!
いや、マジで出たい! マジで出たいな。
Man, I wanted to appear! I really wanted to appear.
もしかしてこの後って... ライブ! そうですよね、ライブですよね!
Could it be that after this... a live! That's right, a live stream, right!
いや、めちゃくちゃ楽しみ、マジ楽しみです!
Man, I'm so excited, I'm seriously so excited!
めっちゃ応援してますマジで! めっちゃ応援し... あ、スバル先輩、スバル先輩!
I'm cheering you on so much, seriously! I'm cheering you... Ah, Subaru-senpai, Subaru-senpai!
いや僕、マジでスバル先輩のこと尊敬してて...
Man, I seriously respect Subaru-senpai...
そうなんです! スバル先輩って可愛いだけじゃなくて、ここが熱くて、いやマジ、ハートが熱くてかっこいいなって思ってて! そう、だからめちゃめちゃリスペクトしてて...
That's right! Subaru-senpai isn't just cute, but her passion—man, her heart is so passionate and cool! Yeah, that's why I respect her so much...
あ、そうなんです、リスパ... あ、リスパ... あ、あ、あ、スバル先輩!
Ah, that's right, respect... Ah, respe... Ah, ah, ah, Subaru-senpai!
いや、マジでマジでマジで！ めっちゃ尊敬してるマジで！
Seriously, seriously, seriously! I respect you so much, seriously!
マジで、え、かわいいですね今日も。え、今日もかわいい！
Seriously, uh, you're so cute today too. Uh, you're so cute today!
え, す、先輩！ ああ、す、先輩！ めっちゃ尊敬してるからマジで！
Uh, s-senpai! Ah, s-senpai! I respect you so much, seriously!
す、先輩！ 先牌僕めっちゃ尊敬してるっ、ばっ、ばっ！
S-senpai! Senpai, I respect you so mu— ba— ba—!
先輩先輩しゃばっしゃばっしゃーて、でて！
Senpai senpai shaba shaba shaate, dete!
あ、じょしっ、あ、じょっ、まっ、まっ、あのあのめっちゃ応援してます今日マジ、がんばってください！
Ah, um, I'm cheering for you so much today, seriously, do your best!
スバルちゃん！
Subaru-chan!
5周年ライブ開催おめでとうございます！ うわー！
Congratulations on holding your 5th Anniversary Live! Woohoo!
ついにこの日が来たんだと、もう団長ニコニコなんですけど、きっとね画面の向こうにいるスバルともも 同じ気持ちだと思います。
Finally this day has come, Dancho is all smiles, but I'm sure Subaru-chan on the other side feels the exact same way.
団長は今日はスバルとものみんなに負けないぐらい画面の向こうで全力でペンライト振っていくと思うので、
Dancho is gonna wave her penlight with all her might on the other side so she won't lose to any of the Subatomos today.
いや本当に楽しみにしてます。オープニング前から駄寄ってるんですけど、今年はね、どんなライブになるのか、スバルちゃん毎年ライブ最高だからもう今から楽しみです！
I've been hyped since before the opening, but Subaru-chan's live is the best every year, so I'm really looking forward to it!
うわあ、楽しみ、楽しみ、楽しみ！ 5周年ライブ、始まる、始まる、始まるー！
Woohoo, I'm so excited! The 5th Anniversary Live is starting!
スバル、5周年おめでとう！ライブがんばれー！
Subaru, congratulations on your 5th anniversary! Do your best on the live!
スバル、ライブがんばれー！
Subaru, do your best on the live!
スバル、ライブがんばれよー！
スバル、ライブがんばれよ！くさっ！
Subaru, do your best on the live! Stinky!
スバル、ライブがんばれー！がんばれー！がんばれー！
Subaru, do your best on the live! Do your best!
LIVE START!!
いつもの一日から抜け出して
Let's escape from the usual day
目が覚めるような冒険の舞台へ
to the stage of an awakening adventure
回る地球儀を目印に
with the spinning globe as a landmark
さあ今会いに行こう特別な一日に
let's go meet now on a special day
緑萌ゆる新しい季節に
In a season where green flourishes,
一人見つめたブルーライト
a single blue light that I gazed upon
顔も知らない友達にも満たないクラスメイト
Classmates I don't even know, not quite friends yet,
想定外の暮らし 妄想した理想と真反対に
An unexpected life, totally opposite to the ideal I imagined
淡々と過ぎる毎日 でもやっと会えるね
Days passing monotonously, but finally we can meet
想像と現実が交わって 高鳴る胸抑えられない
Imagination and reality intersect, my beating chest can't be restrained
約束の場所は 夢見ていた場所
The promised place is the place I dreamed of
忘れられない一日が今始まる
An unforgettable day is starting now
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
The long-awaited today is a special day
日常から少しはみ出して ほらシャッターを切って写し出せば
Let's step out of daily life, look, if you take a photo with the shutter clicked
どうしたって零れるような笑顔ばかり
It will only capture overflowing smiling faces
誰かが言い出して飛び乗ったコースターも お揃いのカチューシャも
The coaster someone started and the matching headbands
かけがえのない瞬間に満ちている 待ち時間さえも愛しく思える
Overflowing with priceless moments, even the wait time is loved
次はどこに行こうか 軽やかに歩く
Where should we go next? Walking light-heartedly
不思議なほどに 気付けば過ぎている時間
Time passes by in a mysterious way before you know it
太陽が沈んだ街を飾る 光が織りなすパレードに 心奪われ
Decorating the city where the sun went down, hearts captivated by the parade of lights
本当に来て良かったな
I'm so glad I came here
待ちに待った今日は特別な日 いつも通りから飛び出して
The long-awaited today is a special day, escape from the usual routine
ほらシャッターを切っても写せない 思い出はいつでも待っている
Look, even if you take a photo, memories are always waiting
いつもの一日から抜け出して
Let's escape from the usual day
目が覚めるような冒険の舞台へ
To the stage of an awakening adventure
回る地球儀を目印に
With the spinning globe as a landmark,
さあ今会いにいこう
let's go meet now
特別な一日に
on a special day.
緑萌ゆる新しい季節に
In a season where green foliage sprouts,
一人見つめたブルーライト
a single blue light that I gazed upon.
顔も知らない友達にも満たされないクラスメイト
Classmates not even friends enough to know their faces,
想定外の暮らしはこんなんじゃない
an unexpected life, this isn't it.
妄想した理想と真反対に
Opposite to my imagined ideals,
淡々と過ぎ去る毎日
days passing by monotonously.
でもやっと会えるね
But finally, I can meet you.
想像と現実が交わって
Imagination and reality intersect,
高鳴る胸抑えられない
and my beating chest can't be contained.
約束の場所は
The promised place is
夢見ていた場所
the place I dreamed of.
忘れられない一日が今始まる
An unforgettable day is starting now.
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
The long-awaited today is a special day.
日常から少しはみ出して
Let's step out a bit from our daily routine,
ほらシャッターを切って写し出せば
look, if we snap a photo and capture it,
ああどうしたって零れるような笑顔ばかり
oh, it's just overflowing smiles.
誰かが言い出し走り乗ったコースターも
The coaster someone suggested and jumped on,
お揃いのカチューシャも
and the matching headbands,
かけがえのない瞬間で溢れてる
overflowing with irreplaceable moments.
待ち時間さえも愛しく思える
Even the wait time feels endearing.
次はどこに行こうか
Where should we go next?
軽やかに歩く
Walking light-heartedly,
不思議なほどに気が付けば過ぎている時間
time passes by mysteriously before we know it.
太陽が沈んだ街を飾る
Decorating the town where the sun has set,
光が織りなすパレードに心奪われ
captivated by the parade woven of light.
噛み締める 本当にここに来れて良かったな
Savoring how truly glad I am to have come here.
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
The long-awaited today is a special day.
いつも通りから飛び出して
Stepping out of the usual routine,
ほらシャッターを切っても写せない
look, even if we snap a photo, it won't capture everything,
思い出がいつでも待っている
memories are always waiting.
春も夏も秋も冬も
Spring, summer, autumn, and winter,
この場所で見つけた笑顔が
the smiles we found in this place
ひらひらといくつも積み重なっていく
pile up flutteringly one after another.
次はいつ会いに行けるかな
I wonder when we can meet again.
当たり前から抜け出して
Stepping out of the ordinary,
限界のない冒険の舞台へ
to the stage of an endless adventure.
回る地球儀を目印に さあ今会いにいこう 特別な一日に
With the spinning globe as a landmark, let's go meet now on a special day.
あなたのアイドル サインはB！ chu！
Your idol, the sign is B! Chu!
やっと会えたね 嬉しいね
We finally met, I'm so happy.
待ち遠しくて足音バタバタしながら
Waiting eagerly, stomping my feet,
今日楽しみで眠れなかったよ
I couldn't sleep because I was so excited today!
緊張なんかしてる場合じゃない
There's no time to be nervous,
一分一秒無駄になってできない
we can't waste a single minute or second!
さあ 始めましょう
Now, let's begin!
手を鳴らせば いらっしゃいませ
Clap your hands, welcome!
「好き」が集まる場所へようこそ
Welcome to the place where "likes" gather!
日常はクローゼットの中
Everyday life is in the closet,
ここに来たなら踊らにゃ損！損！損！
if you came here, you'd lose out if you don't dance!
人がいようがまいが関係ない
It doesn't matter if there are people or not,
箱が大きい小さいとか気にしない
we don't care if the venue is big or small!
ちゃんと見えてる 君のサイリウム
We can see your glow sticks clearly.
今はふうっと吹けば飛ぶような
Like something that would blow away with a puff now,
小さな小さな才能だけど
it's just a tiny, tiny talent, but
私を推してくれるのなら
if you're going to support me,
ファンサをあげる
I'll give you fan service!
あなたのアイドル サインはB！ chu！
Your idol, the sign is B! Chu!
引っ込み思案も人見知りも
Shut-ins and shy people too,
普段と違う顔見せてよ
show me an expression different from usual!
みんな兄弟 調子どうだい
Everyone's my brother, how's it going?
知らんふりかまわずにそう！そう！そう！
Without pretending not to notice, yes! yes! yes!
人に笑われていても関係ない
It doesn't matter if people are laughing at you,
周りがどうこうとか気にしない
we don't care what others say.
主張強すぎ 君のサイリウム
Your glow sticks have too much presence!
たとえ世界が私を拒んで
Even if the world rejects me
ひとりぼっちを感じたとしても
and you feel all alone,
あなたが味方でいてくれたら恐いものはないよ
if you're on my side, there's nothing to be afraid of.
見てよ 見てよ 何か始まる
Look, look, something is beginning,
君との物語が
a story with you.
ああ なんて素晴らしい景色だ！
Ah, what a wonderful view!
人がいようがまいが関係ない
It doesn't matter if there are people or not,
箱が大きい小さいとか気にしない
we don't care if the venue is big or small!
ちゃんと見えてる 君のサイリウム
We can see your glow sticks clearly.
今はふうっと吹けば飛ぶような
Like something that would blow away with a puff now,
小さな小さな才能だけど
it's just a tiny, tiny talent, but
私を推してくれるのなら
if you're going to support me,
ファンサをあげる！
I'll give you fan service!
あなたのアイドル サインはB！ chu！
Your idol, the sign is B! Chu!
奴らが育てたって誇り 将来自慢して欲しいよっこうし
You should proudly brag about how I raised you in the future!
貸し借り恋愛 君と！君と！今を！ 楽しまなきゃ損！損！損！損！
No borrowing and lending in love, enjoy the present with you!
ひとりぼっちを感じたとしても
Even if you feel all alone,
あなたが味方でいてくれたら
if you're on my side,
恐いものはないよ
there's nothing to be afraid of.
見てよ 見てよ 何か始まる
Look, look, something is beginning,
君との物語が
a story with you.
ああ なんて素晴らしい景色だ！
Ah, what a wonderful view!
人がいようがまいが関係ない
It doesn't matter if there are people or not,
箱が大きい小さいとか気にしない
we don't care if the venue is big or small!
ちゃんと見えてる 君のサイリウム
We can see your glow sticks clearly.
今はふうっと吹けば飛ぶような
Like something that would blow away with a puff now,
小さな小さな才能だけど
it's just a tiny, tiny talent, but
私を推してくれるのなら
if you're going to support me,
ファンサをあげる！
I'll give you fan service!
あなたのアイドル サインはB！ chu！
Your idol, the sign is B! Chu!
ア・ナ・タのアイドル
Your idol
サインはB ♡
The distinctive sign is B ♡
ようやく会えたね 嬉しいね
I'm so happy that we finally met!
サインはB！
Wait, the sign is B!
電波テンポアップして
Up the tempo of the frequency
絶賛感電中！
for shocking electricity!
あなたにも忘れたいこと かなしいこと
I wonder if you also have some sad memories
あるのかしらね
that you want to forget?
知らない映画なのに涙を流すのは
Even unrelatable movies make me cry
ドラマチックが足りていないからよ
due to the lack of dramatic moments between us.
そんな愚にも付かないこと くだらないこと考えてばかりね
All I ever think about is absurd and silly things.
嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部今夜のためよ
This foundation of total lies was built just for tonight.
雨が上がれば愛もその横顔も誰かのものになるのでしょう
Once the rain stops, love and this side view will belong to someone else.
なにより一体全体如何して何故？
But what in the world, how on earth, why the hell?
不安定なカンテラ何処まで行くの
How far can we go with this flickering lantern?
あなた一切合切放り去ってもう
You just threw away the whole kit and caboodle.
冗談じゃないわ
You've got to be kidding me!
トウキョウ・シャディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来ったってどうにもならないぜ
Nothing can be done when that moment arrives.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
This unclear reality only makes me more melancholy.
あたしをさあ掠奪して今テイクオンミー
Come snatch me up and right now, take on me.
冗談じゃないわ
Come on!
トウキョウ・シャディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来ったってどうにもならないぜ
Nothing can be done when that moment arrives.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
This unclear reality only makes me more melancholy.
あたしをさあ掠奪して今テイクオンミー Yes!
Come snatch me up and right now, take on me, yes!
はあ ちんちんおかしな法度ばかりで食指がぴくともしないわ
Ha, with all these ridiculous taboos, my appetite isn't stimulated at all.
実態の無い感情放っておいたって策略なんてありゃあしないのに何故
Why leave unembodied emotions alone when there aren't even any schemes involved?
ああもう懲り懲りよ
Ah, I've had enough of this.
あたしの気っとな気質もじっと堪えて取り繕いってはととの臨界点
My fiery nature, kept patiently bottled up while I put on a front, has finally reached its critical point.
年がら年中リップサービス鬱気かましては欺易
Year-round lip service and playing dumb tires me out.
どんがらがっしゅうちゅうフィールガールは涙の目にも鬼
The clattering feel girl is a demon even in tears.
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいであなたの話は一向に聴き取れない
Now, because of the music in my head, I can't catch a single word you're saying.
少しはまともなこと言って
Say something sensible for once.
回り出すターンテーブル
The turntable starts spinning.
ねえ全部忘れさせてよ
Hey, let me forget everything.
だけど一体全体如何して何故？
But what in the world, how on earth, why the hell?
不安定なカンテラ消えない気儘ね
That flickering lantern still hasn't gone out.
あなた一口両舌食い違ってもう
You're speaking with a forked tongue and contradicting yourself.
冗談じゃないわ
You've got to be kidding me!
トウキョウ・シャディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来ったってどうにもならないぜ
Nothing can be done when that moment arrives.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
This unclear reality only makes me more melancholy.
あたしをさあ掠奪して今テイクオンミー
Come snatch me up and right now, take on me.
冗談じゃないわ
Come on!
トウキョウ・シャディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来ったってどうにもならないぜ
Nothing can be done when that moment arrives.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
This unclear reality only makes me more melancholy.
あたしをさあ確かめ合ってエローマジック
Come snatch me up and right now, take on me.
アイアイヤ
Come on!
トウキョウ・シャディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来ったってどうにもならないぜ
Nothing can be done when that moment arrives.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
This unclear reality only makes me more melancholy.
あたしをさあ掠奪して今テイクオンミー Yes!
Come snatch me up and right now, take on me.
はい、ということで！ちわーす！ホロライブ2期生大空スバル！みなさん、楽しんでくれてますかー！
So everyone, thank you so much for coming to the Oozora Subaru 5th Anniversary Live!
めちゃめちゃ嬉しい！
I'm super, super happy!
ぜひね皆さん、このうえでね、「#大空スバル5周年」でこれですねぜひXでポストしてください！
Please post it with the hashtag #OozoraSubaru5thAnniversary!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
じゃあさっきね、決めさせていただいた「サインはB」のこの決めポーズ！
So, the pose we decided on earlier is the "Sign is B" pose!
ぜひね皆さん、これをポスト、よろしくお願いします！
Please post it everyone!
そしてそして「サインはB」ではずわーとコールもさ、みんな来てくれてありがとうございました！
And thank you so much to all the viewers for coming to watch!
ここで前半のちょっとアイドルっぽいパートが1つ終わり！
That wraps up the first half's slightly idol-ish part!
そしてこっからはね、またちょっと何かが変わるかもしれませんので、
And from here on, something might change again,
ぜひそのあたりもお楽しみにしてください！
so please look forward to that as well!
それでは次の曲は……こちら！
Now then, the next song is... right here!
ほらほらまた始まった
C'mon c'mon c'mon here we go again
得意の自己弁護言い訳
Another story made up for me
「でもね」「だって」
"But then..." "Because..."
ほらほらまた始まった
C'mon c'mon c'mon here we go again
ごめん！からキスの方って感じ？
The same old "Sorry, kiss me darling"
簡易
Easy...
“いつかアタシだけ”そんな夢見たこともあったけど
And praying for the day that you would see only me
寂しい時だけ電話して
You're calling when you're lonely
もううんざりだわ！
never for me, leave mine alone!
全然アタシに興味ないじゃん
No no no, you never liked me that way
キミが好きなのは自分でしょう（Yeah!）
Too busy for a girl in love with yourself? (Yeah!)
やっぱりアタシに興味ないじゃん
Shoulda known that you never liked me that way
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I've heard it all before, now I want it to end
そもそもだいたいアタシに興味ないじゃん
Never really did you like me that way
そーやってまた誤魔化して…（もう！）
But here you go again trying to trick my head (No!)
be my boy わがまま過ぎるbaby
Be my boy or be greedier than me baby
抱きしめてよね！
You better grab me and see!
ホントキミはしょうもないな
Dunno, let it go, and "What can I do?"
甘いアタシ「しょうもないな」
Letting him walk? And walk upon you?
泣いたって行かないでって言ったって変わりゃしないや！
Cry and plead and "Please don't leave" / But not a thing is changing!
もう少しだけなら舞い踊ってもいいかもな
Bleeding you dry, you wouldn't mind
とろけてとろけてイキたいの
I melte-te-te-te-ted in your honey lies
どんなアピールも意味ないし気付いてくれないけど
And knowing in my heart, you'll never see me go by
アタシが寂しい時だって逢いに来て！
But then a lonely night, I beg and try to pretend
全然アタシに興味ないじゃん
No no no, you never liked me that way
どこがダメなの？教えてよ（Yeah!）
What part of me that I don't see is failing the test? (Yeah!)
ホントキミはしょうもないな
You really are hopeless
甘いアタシ「しょうもないな」
Such a sweet girl, "how useless"
泣いたって行かないでって言ったって変わりゃしないや
Crying and begging won't change a thing!
もう少しだけなら舞い踊ってもいいかもな
If it's just a little bit, maybe I can dance
とろけてとろけて行きたいの
Melting and dissolving away
どんなアピールも意味ないし気付いてくれないけど
No appeal means anything, and you won't even notice
アタシが寂しい時だって
But even when I'm feeling lonely...
逢いに来て！
Come see me!
全然アタシに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all
どこがダメなのか教えてよ
Tell me what's wrong with me!
やっぱりアタシに興味ないじゃん
You really aren't interested in me after all
携帯ばかりいじってさ
Just playing on your phone all the time
そもそもだいたいアタシに興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you're not interested in me
少し気付かせて
Make me realize it a little bit
ロミオが独り占めてよベイビー
Romeo, hog me all to yourself, baby
振り回さないで！
Don't push me around!
ねぇ、maybe melty?
Hey, maybe melty?
ワン・ツー shall we dance? 踊りましょう
One, two, shall we dance? Let's dance
はやく手と手繋いで
Hurry and hold my hand
最後にひとつだけ
Just one last thing at the end
溺れるくらい愛してよ
Love me enough to drown in it
全然アタシに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all
キミが好きなのは自分でしょう
The one you love is yourself, right?
やっぱりアタシに興味ないじゃん
You really aren't interested in me after all
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm sick of hearing that story
そもそもだいたいアタシに興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you're not interested in me
そーやってまた誤魔化してさ
Just playing dumb like that again
けけらったダンス覚悟はできてるの？
Ready for the devilish dance?
気まぐれメルシィ
Kimagure Mercy
お味はいかが？
How does it taste?
唖々、臨界実験に付き合う朝
Ah, the morning accompanying a critical experiment
14聴(ポンド)を嘲う贅奴(ベッド)
Mocking the 14-pound bed
「何処(どう)しようもないけど」
"There's nothing I can do, but"
気ガ狂ウヒトノ振リヲシテイルキミヲ観テル
Watching you pretending to lose your mind
唖々、面倒だったから切り捨てた
Ah, I cut it off because it was a hassle
4U型(サイズ)を掬う烙句(ラック)
Scooping up the 4U size rack
「申し訳ないけど」
"I'm sorry, but"
擦れ違うモノに無為に期待を背負わせている
Burdening passing things with idle expectations
夜更かしはイドの暴走
Late night is the rampage of the id
目に焼き付いた青の感光
Blue light burned into my eyes
モラトリアム的人生
A moratorium-like life
最大公約数緩衝材
Lowest common multiple buffer
食べてすぐ寝て醜になる
Eat and sleep right away, become ugly
起きてまた寝て人でない？
Wake up and sleep again, are you even human?
失敗！
Fail!
マキシマイザー マキシマイザー！
Maximizer, maximizer!
急転 相まって壊したってDEAD強行！
Sudden turn, breaking together, forcing DEAD!
なんてこった！死んでしまう！
Oh god! I'm gonna die!
だがツマミは回る鵞字引MATE!
But the knob turns, a goose-letter MATE!
サンク コスター サンク コス テス！
Sunk coster, sunk cost tess!
同位体 終いには 取り戻したいって
Isotopes, in the end, wanting to take it back
無間地獄へ堕ちる！堕ちる！
Falling into Avici hell! Falling!
but a 眩み unbalance 乖離 far away!
but a dazzling unbalance divergence far away!
マキシマイザー マキシマイザー！
Maximizer, maximizer!
急転 相まって壊したってDEAD強行！
Sudden turn, breaking together, forcing DEAD!
なんてこった！死んでしまう！
Oh god! I'm gonna die!
だがツマミは回る鵞字引MATE!
But the knob turns, a goose-letter MATE!
サンク コスター サンク コス テス！
Sunk coster, sunk cost tess!
同位体 終いには 取り戻したいって
Isotopes, in the end, wanting to take it back
唾々、臨界実験に伴う朝
The criticality, the morning trial
14聴（ポンド）を嘲う賎奴（ベッド）
of 14 pounds I smirk at all the while
「如何しようもないけど」
"I can't really help it, I know"
気が狂うヒトの真似をしているキミを観ている
I got my eyes on you, the one who claimed his screws are loose
唾々、生還実験に繰り出すアラーム
Revived by the alarm of the morning trial
旧四ロンドを微笑（わら）う劣等
the 14 pounds taunting them all the while
「如何しようもないから」
"There's nothing else for us, you know?"
気が狂うヒトの真似をしているキミへ
I say to you, who's mimicking a lunatic
「簡単な言葉、信じたいなら」
"Such simple words, well if that's what you want to believe - "
── 足りないよ。
- I can't get through
「申し訳ないなら」
"If you're truly sorry you will"
── 既に合う音に不意に会いは求めないよ。
I won't find answers in the sounds that sound the same to you
「後悔はエゴの暴走」
Regret made ego rampant
「手に焼き付いた青の残像」
Blue light branded in my handprint
「モラトリアム的人間」
A moratorium-like life
「最大公約数緩衝材」
The LCD's the guillotine
食べてすぐ寝て牛になる
Eat and sleep right away, becoming a beast
起きてまた寝て人でない？
Wake up, sleep again, are you even human?
「参っちまうな、マキシマイザー」
"I surrender, Maximizer"
救世愛待って焦がしたってFADE凶行
All the love that I burned up for will turn to murder
「なんてことだ、生きてしまう」
"Oh my god! Good god, I'm gonna live!"
だが恨み遡く惨事またgate
But resentment takes my hand and we go to hell again
失敗！（Fail）マキシマイザー マキシマイザー！
Fail! Maximizer, Maximizer!
急転 相まって壊したってDEAD強行！
Though it stopped as it started, we're still as good as dead!
「なんてことだ、死んでしまう！」
"Oh my god, good god we're gonna die!"
だがツマミは回る楔文字MATE！
But the knobs have turned around so we're bound now to comply
サンク コスター サンク コス テス！
Sankukosutaa, sankukosutesu!
同位体 終わりには取り戻したいって
Yet our grips on this isotope won't go to rest
「無間地獄に堕ちる！堕ちる！」
"We're falling down to the last circle of hell!"
But a 眩み unbalance 乖離 far away！
But the dazzling unbalance escapes us, far away!
マキシマイザー マキシマイザー！
Maximizer, Maximizer!
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you now, what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか？
Are you in this endless sky?
今まで私の心を埋めていたモノ
I realized for the first time
失って初めて気付いた
I've lost the things that have filled my heart till now
こんなにも私を支えてくれていたこと こんなにも笑顔をくれていたこと
How much you supported me, how much you made me smile
失ってしまった代償は
That I'd lost them was too much to consider
とてつもなく大きすぎて 取り戻そうと必死に手を探してもがくけれど
Even though I struggled so desperately to reach out my hand and take them back
まるで風のようにすり抜けて届きそうで届かない
Like the wind they slipped through, looking as though they would reach me, but did not
孤独と絶望に胸を締め付けられ
My chest was tightened by loneliness and despair
心が壊れそうになるけれど
My heart felt like it would break
思い出に残るあなたの笑顔が私をいつも励ましてくれる
But your smiling face remained in my memories, always encouraging me
もう一度あの頃に戻ろう
Let's return to those days once more
今度はきっと大丈夫
I know it will be alright this time
いつもそばで笑っていよう あなたのすぐそばで
Always smiling at your side, close by your side
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you now, what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか？
Are you in this endless sky?
いつものように笑顔でいてくれますか？
Will you smile for me like always?
今はただそれを願い続ける
Right now, it's all I continue to ask for.
ガラス玉ひとつ 落とした
A single glass bead was dropped.
追いかけてもうひとつ落っこちた
Chasing after it, another fell.
ひとつ分の陽だまりにひとつだけ残ってる
In a patch of sunlight meant for one, only one remains.
心臓が始まった時
When a heart begins to beat,
嫌でも人は場所をとる
humans take up space whether they want to or not.
奪われないように守り続けてる
Protecting it continuously so it won't be stolen.
汚さずに保ってきた手でも汚れて見えた
Even hands kept unsoiled appeared stained.
記憶を疑う前に記憶に疑われてる
Before doubting memories, I am doubted by memory itself.
必ず僕らは出会うだろう 同じ鼓動の音を目印にして
Surely we will meet, using the sound of the same heartbeat as our guide.
ここに居るよ いつだって呼んでいるから
"I am here," I am calling out to you always.
くたびれた理由が重なって揺れる時 生まれた意味を知る
When tired reasons overlap and waver, we will learn the meaning of being born.
存在が続く限り 仕方ないから場所をとる
As long as existence continues, we inevitably take up space.
ひとつ分の陽だまりに ふたつきはちょっと入れない
Two cannot quite fit into a patch of sunlight meant for one.
ガラス玉ひとつ 落とした 落ちた時何かすき出した
A single glass bead was dropped; when it fell, it pushed something out.
奪い取った場所で 光を浴びた
In the space taken by force, it bathed in the light.
数えた足跡など 気づけば数字でしかない
The footsteps counted, before realizing it, are nothing more than numbers.
知らなきゃいけないことは どうやらイチとゼロの間
What we must learn lies somewhere between 1 and 0.
初めて僕らは出会うだろう 同じ悲鳴の旗を目印にして
For the first time we will meet, using the flag of the same scream as our guide.
忘れないで いつだって呼んでいるから
Don't forget, I am calling out to you always.
重なった理由を 二人で埋める時 約束が交わされる
When the two of us bury our accumulated reasons, a promise will be made.
鏡なんだぼくらお互いに それぞれのカルマを写すための
We are mirrors to each other to reflect our respective karma.
汚れた手と手で触れ合って 形がわかる
By touching with our stained hands, we understand each other's form.
ここに居るよ 確かに触れるよ
"I am here, I can truly feel you."
ひとり分の陽だまりにぼくらは居る
In a patch of sunlight meant for one person, we exist.
忘れないで いつだって呼んでいるから
Don't forget, I am calling out to you always.
同じガラス玉の 内側の方から そうさ必ず 僕らは出会うだろう
That's right, surely we will meet from the inside of the same glass bead.
沈めた理由に十字架を立てる時 約束が果される
When we erect a cross upon the reasons we submerged, the promise will be fulfilled.
ぼくらひとつになる
We will become one.
必ず 僕らは出会うだろう 同じ鼓動の音を目印にして
Surely we will meet, using the sound of the same heartbeat as our guide.
ここに居るよ いつだって呼んでいるから
"I am here," I am calling out to you always.
沈めた理由に十字架を立てる時 約束は果たされる
When tired reasons overlap and waver, we will learn the meaning of being born.
ぼくらはひとつになる
We will become one.
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
何処へ行ったの？
Where did you go?
聴こえますか？
Can you hear me?
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう
How much more do I have to shout?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう
How much more do I have to cry?
もうやめて わたしはもう走れない
Stop already, I can't run anymore.
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing.
真っ暗で明かりもない 崩れかけたこの道で
On this pitch-dark, unlit, crumbling road,
あるはずもない あの時の希望が
I felt like I could see the hope from back then
見えた気がした
Which shouldn't even exist.
照して ブラック★ロックシューター
Illuminate me, Black Rock Shooter.
懐かしい記憶
Nostalgic memories,
ただ楽しかった あの頃を
Of those purely fun times back then.
ブラック★ロックシューター でも動けないよ
Black Rock Shooter, but I can't move.
闇を駆ける星に願いを
I wish upon the star racing through the darkness,
もう一度だけ走るから
Because I'll run just once more.
恐くて震える声でつぶやく
I whisper with a voice trembling with fear,
わたしの名前を呼んで
Call my name.
夜明けを抱く空 境界線までの距離
The sky embracing dawn, the distance to the boundary line,
あと一歩届かない
Unable to reach it by just one more step.
こぼれた涙が溢れそうなの
The spilled tears are about to overflow,
今下を向かないで 止まってしまう
Don't look down now, or I'll come to a stop.
未来を生きていたいんだ
I want to live in the future.
わかったの 思い出して
I understand now, remembering,
強く強く信じるの
Believing firmly, firmly.
そうよ ブラック★ロックシューター
That's right, Black Rock Shooter,
優しい匂い
A gentle scent.
「いたいよ」「つらいよ」
"It hurts," "It's tough,"
飲み込む言葉
Swallowing those words.
動いてこの足！
Move, these legs!
世界を超えて！
Beyond the world!
最初から分かっていた ここにいることを
I knew from the beginning that I was here.
私の中の全ての勇気が
All the courage inside of me
火をともして もう逃げないよ
Lights the fire, I won't run away anymore.
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
ひとりじゃないよ
You're not alone.
声を上げて泣いたって構わない
I don't mind even if you cry out loud.
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
見ていてくれる
You're watching over me.
今から始まるの
It starts from now,
私の物語
My story.
忘れそうになったら この歌を
When you're about to forget, this song
歌うの！
Will be sung!
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
見ていてくれる
You're watching over me,
今から始まるの
It starts from now,
私の物語
My story.
忘れそうになったら この歌を
When you're about to forget, this song
歌うの
You sing it.
描いた未知のキャンバス 重ねる景色
Painted canvas of the unknown, overlapping scenery,
繋いでみて 繰り返していく衝動
Connecting them, impulses repeating over and over,
揺らいだ目の前に 広がる世界
Before my wavering eyes, a spreading world,
星屑のメロディ 歌にのせた
A stardust melody set to song.
クラッと鮮やかに 眩ませるように
So vividly dizzying, dazzlingly bright,
駆け抜けろよ スターライト
Run right through it, starlight!
We can fly そう僕らは
We can fly, yes, we
いつしか 夢の中 引かれて
Before we knew it, drawn into a dream,
ただがむしゃらに 走り続けたよ
We just kept running on recklessly.
無限の宇宙に 響いたキミを照らす声は
The voice illuminating you echoing in the infinite universe
どこへだってきらり 飛んでいけるんだ
Can brilliantly fly anywhere.
陽気な仲間と 歩いた非日常
An extraordinary time walked with cheerful friends,
掴んでみて 指先の一等星
Try grabbing it, the first-magnitude star at your fingertips.
滲んでいく目の前に 広がった限界は
The limit that spread before my blurring eyes
みんなの手重ねて ぶっ壊して
Stacked everyone's hands and smashed it to pieces.
吸い込まれそうな 夜空を見上げて
Looking up at the night sky that looks like it'll swallow us,
今叫ぶよ スターライト
Now I shout out, starlight!
I wanna be そう僕らは
I wanna be, yes, we
いつでも傍で 笑い合って
Always smiling side by side,
あふれる声が 遠くこだまする
Overflowing voices echoing far away.
願いのかけらを 灯したキミの腕を引いて
Pulling the arm of you who lit the fragments of our wish,
どこへだってきらり 飛んでいけるんだ
We can brilliantly fly anywhere.
ちょっと不安な日も 魔法をかけてハッピー
Even on slightly uneasy days, cast a spell for happiness,
百人力で 乗り越えていこう
Let's overcome it with superhuman strength!
アクアブルーに染まる 大空めがけた
The heartbeat aiming at the wide sky
鼓動が弾んでく
Dyed in aqua blue is bouncing!
We can fly そう僕らは
We can fly, yes, we
この日をずっと 待ってたんだ まだ覚めないで
Have been waiting for this day all along, don't wake up yet.
Starlight 僕らは止まらない
Starlight, we won't stop,
その光が 消える1秒前まで 走り続けるよ
We'll keep running until one second before that light fades.
無限の宇宙に 響いたキミを照らす声は
The voice illuminating you echoing in the infinite universe
強く抱いてきらり 輝いていけ
Hold it tight and go on shining brilliantly.
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
Shine bright!
呼び合う声を 合図に
Taking voices calling out to each other as our cue,
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探しにゆく
We're going to search!
スタートは 何度だって
No matter how many times we start over.
ただ 独り言を綴った
I simply penned down a soliloquy,
ただ 始まりたくて走った
I simply ran because I wanted it to begin.
遠く 暗がりにとまった
It stopped far away in the gloom,
それは 眩し過ぎた名前
That was a name too dazzling,
それは 優し過ぎる思い出もずっと
And memories far too kind...
過ぎ去る思い出 もっと
Passing memories, even more...
近づけと手を伸ばした
I reached out to get closer.
思いがけず 結び合った
Unexpectedly, we connected.
ほら 今 迷子は “僕等” になった
Look, now the lost children have become "us."
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright.
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring along both frustration and love.
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, feathers—you can take flight.
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなき 兆し
A modest prayer is light, an endless sign.
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
I can be proud that I found you.
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here, from now on, our bright parade, parade!
まだ 頼りない予感を
Still feeling uncertain about this premonition,
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんないよ
let's sing, there's nothing to be embarrassed about.
誰も解けない イマジナリー
An imaginary world no one can unlock.
いつか また逢える おまじない
A spell so we can meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
The story that began at zero on that day.
数え切れない 言の葉 数えるような 想いじゃないさ
Countless words—it's not a feeling you can just count.
ほら 今 “僕等” を 一つと 呼ぼう
Look, now let's call "us" one.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 美しいんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's so beautiful.
許し合える 刹那 夜は きらめく
A fleeting moment of mutual forgiveness, the night sparkles.
雨 晴れ カレイド まだ見ない空
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope, a yet-unseen sky.
相応しい 旅路とは 君と在ることさ
A fitting journey is being right by your side.
君と在ることなんだ
Yes, being right by your side.
“ただいま”って聞けば “おかえり”って叫ぶよ
When I hear "I'm home," I'll shout "Welcome back."
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that only natural?
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright.
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ！
What fills the darkness is you, it's me!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright.
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring along both frustration and love.
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, feathers—you can take flight.
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなき 兆し
A modest prayer is light, an endless sign.
君と飛び込んでゆく 素敵なスタートさ
Diving in together with you, what a wonderful start.
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here, from now on, our bright parade, parade!
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
はーい、ということで、えー2期生のみんなとね、
Hi there! So, along with the 2nd gen members,
Stellar Stellar、そしてOur Bright Parade、そしてですね、スバルでブラックロックシューターをお届けできましたー！おー！
we delivered Stellar Stellar, Our Bright Parade, and even Subaru's Black Rock Shooter! Woo!
ちょっとね、結構こう、盛りだくさんな内容だったと思うんですけれども、
It was quite a packed setlist, I think,
もう本当にね、一緒に踊ってくれた、え、バックダンサーの皆さん、そしてね2期生の皆さんありがとうございましたー！
but I really want to thank all the backup dancers who danced with us and all the 2nd gen members! Thank you so much!
はーい、ということで、ここでなんと活動5周年記念グッズがでまーす！こちら！
Alright, and with that, my 5th anniversary commemorative merchandise is now available! Check this out!
活動5周年記念フルセット
[5th Anniversary Full Set]
お！出でますねえ。えー、B2タペストリー！これはですね、しぐれういかあちゃんのお墨付きのB2のタペストリーです！
Oh! There it is. A B2 tapestry! This is an officially approved B2 tapestry featuring Shigure Ui-kaachan's illustration!
ぜひねお部屋に一緒に飾ってください。ちょっとね服なんかもね、あの、ちょっとこう特別のね、5周年ぽい、ちょっと、こうドレスみたいなのきてます！かわいい！
Please display it together in your room. The outfit is also a special, 5th-anniversary-style dress! So cute!
しゅぱっ！ジャージ ということでね、スバルといえばまあジャージなんですけど、まあスバルもねこれを着てねダンスレッスンやね、えスタジオの中に行きたいと思いますのでねぜひみんなも一緒に着てお揃いにしましょう！
Shupa! Jersey. Well, speaking of Subaru, it's jerseys! I'd love to wear this for dance lessons in the studio too, so let's all wear it together and match!
しゅぱっ！キャップ！これはマジでいい。もう本当に、これはもうスバルが欲しくて作ったものがあるんですけど、これねしゅぱって書いてあるね、スバルのお尻だよ
Shupa! Cap! This is seriously great. I really wanted this and had it made—it has "SHUPA!" written on it, and it's Subaru's butt!
ぜひ着ながら使えるキャップとなっております
These caps are designed to be worn
黒なのでね ぜひねアクターにもおすすめです
and since they're black, I definitely recommend them!
アクターよかったがぶってね
Hololive actors, please wear one!
それでは続いてこちら！
And now, moving on to this!
しゅばっ！靴下！ということで
Shuba socks! So,
えーこれはですねスバルが靴下がほしくてね
um, these are... Subaru wanted socks,
すみませんスバルが 欲しいから作りました
so— I mean, because I wanted them, we made them!
ぜひねみんなもねこんな可愛いねスバルダックのワンポイント靴下を履いて
So everyone, please wear these cute one-point Shuba Duck socks
学校やお仕事やジムやレッスンに よかったら行ってみてください！
to school, work, the gym, or lessons if you'd like!
はい、そしてなんとですねフルセットは 箔押し複製サイン&メッセージ入りとなっております。
And for the full set, it comes with a foil-stamped duplicate signature and message!
え、こちはですねしぐれういかあちゃんの描き下ろしポストカードです！
This is an illustration postcard drawn by Shigure Ui-mama!
そしてですねなんと今回 数量限定ではございません！
And you know what, this time there is no quantity limit!
よろしくお願いします！数量限定ではないのでみんなね買うタイミングで買ってみてください！
Thank you! There's no limit, so please buy them whenever you'd like!
はい、そしてもう一つお知らせがあります！
Yes, and I have one more announcement!
なんとですね この後22:00に新曲のPVが公開されます！
At 22:00 tonight, the MV for my new song will premiere!
新曲…新曲、そう！
New song... New song, yes!
最後のね、曲に行こうと思うんですけど、最後の曲は新曲です！
We're moving on to the final song, and the last song is a brand new track!
この曲はですね、ま、スバルもね5年間活動してきたわけなんですけれども
This song... Subaru has been active for 5 years now,
この5年間のスバルの活動を支えてくれたファンのみんなやメンバーのねみんなのことを考えて作りました！
and I made it while thinking of all the fans and members who supported my activities over these 5 years!
5周年をねこうやってみんなと迎えられて本当に嬉しいです！いつもたくさんの応援ありがとう！
I'm so happy to celebrate our 5th anniversary together like this! Thank you always for all your support!
というですね、感謝を込めてここを頑張って歌いたいと思うので、よかったら聴いてください！
Putting my gratitude into words, I'll do my best to sing it, so please listen!
それでは聴いてください、「Stellar Symphony」！
Please listen to 'Stellar Symphony'!
手を伸ばせば
If I reach out my hand,
届きそうな
it feels within reach,
空に輝く
shining in the sky,
希望の光
the light of hope.
星は巡り合う
Stars cross paths,
願い求め
seeking a wish,
奇跡と出会う
meeting a miracle,
その日を
awaiting that day.
寄り添い 輝く 愛を抱え
Holding close shining love,
煌めく熱は 空駆け伝う
sparkling warmth races across the sky.
きらり 光る 星は集い
Glittering, shining stars gather,
私 包まれてたんだ
and I was embraced.
願い 奏でる 空に
In the sky where wishes play,
一つずつ 輝く 意味を灯して
lighting up the meaning of each sparkle one by one,
泣いて 光る明日 描いて
crying, drawing a shining tomorrow.
星は巡る 愛を乗せて
Stars revolve, carrying love,
私のすべて 届きますように
hoping my everything reaches you.
願い込め 歌うから
Pouring my wish into song,
星を撫でて I love you
I stroke the stars, I love you.
大空を滑るのは 君と私
Crossing the great sky is you and me,
通わせて 想いを
letting our feelings resonate.
星を連ね Shine with you
Connecting the stars, Shine with you,
描いた夢 目指して 歩もう
aiming for the dream we drew, let's walk on.
瞬く きらり 光る 星は満ちて
Twinkling, glittering, shining stars fill the sky,
私 照らし出されていた 確かな 奇跡 描いて
and I was illuminated, drawing a certain miracle.
涙さえも 時を超えて 光って
Even tears transcend time and shine.
手を伸ばせば 届きそうな
If I reach out my hand, it feels within reach,
空に輝く 皆の光
everyone's light shining in the sky.
共歩んだこと 君がくれた愛を
The path we walked together, the love you gave me,
幾重もの運命を 抱きしめて
embracing countless destinies,
私輝くから あなたを照らすから
because I will shine, because I will illuminate you,
大空を滑るんだ 未知へと
gliding across the great sky toward the unknown.
君と私 通わせて想いを
You and me, letting our feelings resonate.
星を連ね Shine with you
Connecting the stars, Shine with you,
描いた夢 目指して 歩もう
aiming for the dream we drew, let's walk on.
確かな 軌跡描いて
Drawing a certain trajectory.
いつもの一日から抜け出して
Escaping from the usual day
目が覚めるような冒険の舞台へ
To the stage of an awakening adventure
ようやく会えたね 嬉しいね
I'm so happy that we finally met
待ち遠しくて 足をバタバタさせながら
My legs were swinging while waiting anxiously
電波テンポアップして絶賛感電中！
Radio wave tempo up, feeling electrified!
あなたにも忘れないこと かなしいことがあるのかしらね
I wonder if there are things you can't forget or feel sad about
ほらほらまたはじまった お得意の自己弁護言い訳
Look, here it goes again, your favorite self-justifying excuses
「でもね」「だって」 ほらほらまたはじまった
"But..." "Because..." Look, here it goes again
ごめん！からのごまかしのパターンって感じ？簡易
"Sorry!" followed by a cover-up pattern, you feel? So simple
“いつかアタシだけ”そんな夢見たこともあったけれど
"Someday only me"—I even dreamed of that once, but
寂しい時だけ電話して もううんざりだわ！
Calling only when you're lonely, I'm already sick of it!
孤独と絶望に胸を締め付けられ
My chest is squeezed with loneliness and despair
心が壊れそうになるけれど
My heart feels like it's going to break, but
思い出に残るあなたの笑顔が
Your smiling face remaining in my memories
私をいつも励やしてくれる
Always encourages me
ガラス玉ひとつ 落とされた 追いかけてもうひとつ落っこちた
A single glass bead was dropped; chasing after it, another fell
ひとつ分の陽だまりに ひとつだけ残っている
In a patch of sunlight meant for one, only one remains
心臓が始まった時 嫌でも人は場所を取る
When a heart begins to beat, humans take up space whether they want to or not
ブラックロックシューター 何処へ行ったの？ 聴こえますか？
Black Rock Shooter, where did you go? Can you hear me?
あとどれだけ叫えばいいのだろう あとどれだけ泣けばいいのだろう
How much more do I have to scream? How much more do I have to cry?
もうやめて わたしはもう走れない
Stop already, I can't run anymore
Parade! 輝くんだよ 呼び合う声を 合図に
Parade! It's time to shine, using calling voices as our signal
探しにいく スタートは 何度だって
Going to search, the start is however many times it takes
願い込めて 歌うから
Pouring my wish into song, so
星を撫でて I love you
Stroke the stars, I love you
大空を統べるのは 君と私
Ruling the great sky is you and me